<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: oop | Nicolás Hock Isaza]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.nhocki.com/blog/categories/oop/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.nhocki.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-01-15T22:51:49-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.nhocki.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Nicolás Hock Isaza]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mixing Presenters and Helpers]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.nhocki.com/2012/05/08/mixing-presenters-and-helpers/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-08T18:28:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.nhocki.com/2012/05/08/mixing-presenters-and-helpers</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I just finished <a href="http://pragprog.com/book/warv/the-rails-view">The Rails View</a> and the best chapter for me was about presenters. I've been <a href="http://blog.nhocki.com/2012/01/31/thoughts-on-decorators-and-presenters/">working with this</a> for a while and I have to admit I love the approach presented on the view.</p>

<p>All the presenters I've done were <a href="http://blog.nhocki.com/2012/01/10/simple-presenters--decorators-on-rails/">instantiated in the controller</a>. In the book they suggest that <strong>if the presenter doesn't depend on params or session variables it's the view responsibility to create it</strong>. This is extremely flexible specially when we're presenting various objects on the same view. Here's an example to present users in our application, let's use the same presenter for the <em>index</em> and <em>show</em> actions, but let's make it in a really simple way!</p>

<h3>The Helper &amp; View</h3>

<p>Let's create the helper method first. It's really simple and will take a block that we can use to build a custom markup "on the fly".</p>

<p><div><script src='https://gist.github.com/2640442.js?file=user_helpers.rb'></script>
<noscript><pre><code># app/helpers/user_helpers.rb
def basic_information_for(user = @user, options = {})
  presenter = UserBasicPresenter.new(user, self, options)
  if block_given?
    yield(presenter)
  else
    presenter
  end
end</code></pre></noscript></div>
</p>

<p>Now, let's take a look at the views. In the <strong>show</strong> action, we're going to present only one user, and we can easily build the custom view for this. In the <strong>index</strong> action, we'll present all a "basic info" for the each user. We have that in a partial because this is used for all the collections of users in our application. Here's the view code:</p>

<p><div><script src='https://gist.github.com/2640442.js?file=user_views.html.erb'></script>
<noscript><pre><code># app/views/show.html.erb
&lt;% basic_information_for do |user|  %&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;%= user.name %&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;%= user.status %&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  ...
&lt;% end %&gt;

# app/views/index.html
&lt;% @users.each do |user| %&gt;
  &lt;%= basic_information_for(user) %&gt;
&lt;% end %&gt;</code></pre></noscript></div>
</p>

<h3>The Presenter, A.K.A What's happening here?</h3>

<p>What makes this <strong>really</strong> clean is that we can actually use <code>&lt;%=  %&gt;</code> directly on our helper method. This works because we'll define the <code>to_s</code> method in our presenter! In this method we <strong>render our partial in the context of the helper</strong>, which is amazing. Here's the code for that:</p>

<p><div><script src='https://gist.github.com/2640442.js?file=user_basic_presenter.rb'></script>
<noscript><pre><code># app/presenters/user_basic_presenter.rb
class UserBasicPresenter
  def initialize(user, template, options = {})
    @user     = user
    @options  = options
    @template = template
  end

  # more methods ...

  def to_s
    @template.render partial: 'user/basic', object: self
  end
end</code></pre></noscript></div>
</p>

<p>Is <strong>that</strong> simple! We have a unique interface (the helper) that will work great in both places! We could obviously make the presenter more complex, otherwise, why use it?</p>

<p>Even though I haven't used this approach a lot, I'm really happy with it. I felt the difference instantly and it made a lot of sense to me. Being able to mix this with a <a href="http://blog.nhocki.com/2012/03/29/flexible-and-friendly-layouts-on-rails/">flexible layout</a> is really powerful!</p>

<h3>Feedback</h3>

<p>I'm also really interested in how people are using presenters. I'd love to gain more feedbacks and points of view about this. Feel free to post a comment (here on in the gist) or ping me on Twitter, <a href="https://twitter.com/nhocki">@nhocki</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Thoughts on Decorators & Presenters]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.nhocki.com/2012/01/31/thoughts-on-decorators-and-presenters/"/>
    <updated>2012-01-31T18:12:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.nhocki.com/2012/01/31/thoughts-on-decorators-and-presenters</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I have been developing a new app using a lot of <a href="http://blog.nhocki.com/2012/01/10/simple-presenters--decorators-on-rails/">decorators and presenters</a>. I've been highly influenced by <a href="http://about.avdi.org/">Avdi</a> (both his <a href="http://avdi.org/devblog/">blog</a> and his <a href="http://avdi.org/devblog/2011/11/15/early-access-beta-of-objects-on-rails-now-available-2/">Objects in Rails book</a>) and <a href="http://steveklabnik.com">Steve Klabnik</a>, but now I have a problem. My decorators are starting to get big. I'll have to use <code>concerns</code> for that. Expect another post about it (maybe).</p>

<p><strong>I want to warn you that I am not by any means an expert on the subject. So I'm more than open to any feedback you can give me.</strong></p>

<blockquote><p>All presenters are decorators, but not all decorators are presenters.</p>

<p>A decorator is a class that adds some sort of functionality to another
class. A presenter is a class that adds some sort of presentation
formatting functionality to another class.</p>

<p><a href="https://groups.google.com/forum/#!msg/objects-on-rails/htAopf3k_dM/qJMq6QAfMvsJ">Steve Klabnik</a></p></blockquote>

<p>I think that what a decorator <em>should</em> do is give a standard API for the processed data stored somewhere (probably a database). I don't think a decorator should be in charge of the markup of the presented data. For me, it makes no sense that the decorator (that is processed data for me), knows <em>how</em> it is being shown to the user.</p>

<p>That said, I think the <strong>same</strong> decorator should be used to build the JSON response and the HTML response. The HTML markup and JSON structure are <em>just</em> \'markup\'. So, they can be treated as templates.</p>

<h3>So, where do the logic in the template goes?</h3>

<p>I had this discussion with a <a href="http://mheroin.com/">friend</a>, and he asked me that, with this approach, how would he add elements to a view depending on a condition, for example, the famous \'<strong><em>You are logged in as nhocki</em></strong>\' if there's a user logged in.</p>

<p>I think this should be created inside helper methods that takes a block. Inside that block you can use the <strong>decorator</strong> methods to show the needed data. You can use those methods in your JSON builder too (try out the new <a href="https://github.com/rails/jbuilder">Jbuilder</a>). You could bundle up these methods and re-use them in your projects too.</p>

<p>Here's an example:</p>

<p><div><script src='https://gist.github.com/1714913.js?file='></script>
<noscript><pre><code># app/models/user.rb
#
# User model has name &amp; username
#
# Only the username is required (signup with Github for example)
class User &lt; ActiveRecord::Base
  validates :username, presence: true
end



# app/decorators/user_decorator.rb
#
# Let's use the Draper gem for the decorators
class UserDecorator &lt; ApplicationDecorator
  decorates :user

  def display_name
    user.name.presence || user.username
  end

  # Formatting the data is OK. I'm against adding the markup
  def salary
    h.number_to_currency(user.salary)
  end
end


# app/views/users/index.html.erb

# current_user is a presenter
&lt;%= logged_in_area do %&gt;
  You are logged in as &lt;%= current_user.display_name %&gt;
&lt;% end %&gt;

# viewing @some_users's profile (which is also a presenter)
&lt;%= admin_area do %&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;salary&quot;&gt;&lt;%= @some_user.salary %&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;% end %&gt;


# app/helpers/application_helpers.rb
#
# We all hate helpers, but this time, they're useful.
def admin_area(&amp;block)
  content_tag(:div, capture(&amp;block), class: 'admin') if current_user.admin?
end</code></pre></noscript></div>
</p>

<h3>Maybe I have the names wrong</h3>

<p>As I mentioned before, I'm no expert on design patterns. And I'm pretty <em>new</em> to presenters and decorators. So, maybe my approach has a different name. I don't really care how this is called, I feel it's a more natural approach and it keeps the template and the processed data in different parts.</p>

<h3>Please provide feedback</h3>

<p>It is also possible that I have it all wrong, that's why I'm really interested in your opinion. I'm eager to learn about everything from anyone, so I would love to have some feedback about this. You can post a comment below or send me a message on <a href="http://twitter.com/nhocki">twitter</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Simple Presenters & Decorators on Rails]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.nhocki.com/2012/01/10/simple-presenters--decorators-on-rails/"/>
    <updated>2012-01-10T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.nhocki.com/2012/01/10/simple-presenters--decorators-on-rails</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>There's been a <a href="http://blog.steveklabnik.com/posts/2011-09-06-the-secret-to-rails-oo-design">lot</a> of <a href="http://blog.steveklabnik.com/posts/2011-09-09-better-ruby-presenters">talk</a> <a href="http://avdi.org/devblog/2011/11/15/early-access-beta-of-objects-on-rails-now-available-2/">about</a><a href="http://robots.thoughtbot.com/post/14825364877/evaluating-alternative-decorator-implementations-in">decorators</a> and <a href="http://robots.thoughtbot.com/post/13641910701/tidy-views-and-beyond-with-decorators">presenters</a> (<a href="https://groups.google.com/forum/#!msg/objects-on-rails/htAopf3k_dM/qJMq6QAfMvsJ">which are almost the same</a>) in Rails and how they help you with a "real" OO code. There are great gems and there's even a <a href="http://railscasts.com/episodes/287-presenters-from-scratch">Railscast</a> (pro) on how to build a presenter from scratch. But, in the new project I'm working on, we (&lt;- <a href="https://github.com/febuiles">he</a>) has this <strong>really</strong> simple setup which I feel kind of cleaner.</p>

<p>What we wanted to have was a <code>present</code> method in the controller and build the view from its methods. So, we created an <a href="http://api.rubyonrails.org/classes/ActiveSupport/Concern.html">ActiveSupport::Concern</a> called <code>Presentable</code> and included it in our application controller. Here's our (once again, his) code for that module.</p>

<p><div><script src='https://gist.github.com/1592754.js?file=presentable.rb'></script>
<noscript><pre><code># app/concerns/controllers/presentable.rb

# Presentable Concern
# Include this module in the controllers where
# you need the `present` method.
module Presentable
  # This method returns a Presenter Object to work
  # with in the view.
  #
  # Attributes:
  #   object:   The object to present
  #
  # Supported Options
  #    as:   The presenter class. If this is not suplied 
  #          the method will try to guess the class
  #          e.g: UserPresenter for a User object.
  def present(object, options = { })
    if object.respond_to?(:first)
      return [] if object.empty?
      presenter = &quot;#{object.first.class.to_s.pluralize}Presenter&quot;
    else
      presenter = &quot;#{object.class}Presenter&quot;
    end

    presenter = options.fetch(:as) { eval(presenter) }
    presenter.new(object)
  end
end
</code></pre></noscript></div>
</p>

<p>Now, we just need to create each presenter. But, since there's a lot of shared logic between presenters we (he) just created a parent <code>Presenter class</code> with all that. Notice that our presenter takes an object as parameter, so we just delegated all the method calls to our record (thank you <code>method missing</code>) if it responded to that method. You could also send the view context to access Rails helpers inside your presenter. Here's our <code>Presenter base class</code>.</p>

<p><div><script src='https://gist.github.com/1592754.js?file=presenter.rb'></script>
<noscript><pre><code># Base presenter class
# All presenters should inherit from this one.
class Presenter
  # Include all the modules you need or
  # send the view context to access rails helpers.
  include Rails.application.routes.url_helpers
  # ...

  include Presentable

  attr_reader :record

  def initialize(record)
    @record = record
    @klass = record.class
  end

  def method_missing(name, *arguments, &amp;block)
    super unless record.respond_to?(name)
    record.send(name, *arguments, &amp;block)
  end

  def translate_field_name(name)
    @klass.human_attribute_name(name)
  end

  # UrlHelper was being an ass, easier to go commando.
  def link_to(name, url, options={})
    href = { :href =&gt; url }
    content_tag(:a, name, options.merge(href))
  end
end
</code></pre></noscript></div>
</p>

<p>Then, we just need to inherit from the <code>Presenter</code> class and add our custom, clean methods. Using <code>delegate and method missing</code> will help us keep the class clean. I won't show you a presenter here, they'll look a lot like Ryan's one in his Railscasts so check that out first.</p>

<p>I will show you our controller though. Using the decent_exposure gem we managed to get super tiny controllers. Here's 1 of them:</p>

<p><div><script src='https://gist.github.com/1592754.js?file=requests_controller.rb'></script>
<noscript><pre><code>class RequestsController &lt; ApplicationController
  expose(:filter) { params.fetch(:filter) { :all} }
  expose(:filtered_requests) { Request.filter(filter) }
  expose(:requests) { present(filtered_requests) }

  before_filter :find_request, :only =&gt; [:show, :destroy]

  def index
  end

  def show
    extend(RequestRedirector) # Another concern
    redirect_to_request
  end

  def destroy
    @request.destroy
    redirect_to requests_path(:filter =&gt; &quot;new_requests&quot;), :notice =&gt; &quot;Se ha eliminado la solicitud&quot;
  end

  private
  def find_request
    @request = Request.find(params[:id])
  end
end
</code></pre></noscript></div>
</p>

<p>Combining <code>presenters</code> and <code>form builders</code> will make your views even cleaner, giving a lot of pleasure to the future you! So please, just pretty-please, start using presenters and builders and leave helpers as simple as possible. Or, leave them for good.</p>

<p>You'll be amazed how different you'll feel when reading some old code or some co-worker's code.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
