<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Octopress | Nicolás Hock Isaza]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.nhocki.com/blog/categories/octopress/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.nhocki.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-04-10T20:35:25-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.nhocki.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Nicolás Hock Isaza]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[From Tumblr to Octopress]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.nhocki.com/2012/01/23/from-tumblr-to-octopress/"/>
    <updated>2012-01-23T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.nhocki.com/2012/01/23/from-tumblr-to-octopress</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I wrote an article yesterday about URL design and I spent about an hour fighting with <a href="http://tumblr.com/">Tumblr</a> to format my <code>code inside a pre (or code) tag</code>. I knew I was done with them. Today, I'm giving <a href="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</a> a try. I honestly wanted to try <a href="http://jekyllrb.com/">Jekyll</a> but I was really lazy to code my HTML. So, for now, I'm welcoming Octopress.</p>

<p>I really love the fact that I can write in <a href="http://daringfireball.net/projects/markdown/">Markdown</a>, it's really powerful yet simple that makes me focus on writing and not formatting. I know I can use Markdown in Tumblr but I don't have Textmate there, so this is a big +1 for Jekyll/Octopress.</p>

<h2>Moving Posts From Tumblr</h2>

<p>There's a <a href="https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll/wiki/Blog-Migrations">great script</a> to move posts from Tumblr. They'll even be downloaded as markdown, but I still had to edit them to add the Gist snippets. Thankfully I don't have a lot of posts so it didn't took a lot.</p>

<h2>Deploying</h2>

<p>I've deployed my blog to <a href="http://heroku.com">Heroku</a> now. It was supposed to be really simple. It was, after I realized that the <code>public</code> folder is ignored by the git. I spent an hour of my life there :-( !</p>

<pre>Remove the public folder from your .gitignore</pre>


<p>I'll probably post more about Octopress when I get to know it better. There are a bunch of plugins and stuff that may be useful, or maybe, it'll suck and I'll have to go and find something else!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
