<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: random thoughts | Nicolás Hock Isaza]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.nhocki.com/blog/categories/random-thoughts/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.nhocki.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-03-07T21:27:29-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.nhocki.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Nicolás Hock Isaza]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Seriously just do it]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.nhocki.com/2012/07/26/seriously-just-do-it/"/>
    <updated>2012-07-26T01:07:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.nhocki.com/2012/07/26/seriously-just-do-it</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I have finished my first &quot;working season&quot; at <a href="http://mit.edu">MIT</a>. I got here
on October 4. It&#39;s been an amazing and weird journey.</p>

<p>But I have to admit that at first I was a bad employee. I was <strong>really</strong> used
to have somebody telling me what to do all the time. When I arrived at MIT that
didn&#39;t happen. <strong>At all</strong>. I was given some &quot;long term&quot; tasks and that was it.
I just had to do them.</p>

<p>Since no one was all over me checking my progress or asking me how I was
doing on everything, I was waisting a lot (*most*) of my time.
<a href="http://www.espndeportes.com">ESPNDeportes</a> got a lot of visits from me.
I started using Facebook on regular basis. <a href="http://www.threadless.com">Threadless</a>
didn&#39;t have enough T-shirts for me. <a href="http://twitter.com/nhocki">Twitter</a> was
not &quot;real time enough&quot;...</p>

<p>But, with time, I started working and I can&#39;t say how grateful I am for <a href="http://tomayko.com/writings/management-style">this
way of managing</a>. I&#39;ve learned
to be much more productive on my own. To manage my time. To be much more
responsible. But, I guess the best thing about this was that I learned that
you just need to <strong>shut up, close all the meaningless things you have open and
get shit done</strong>.</p>

<p>Sure, if you need help, ask. If what you&#39;re doing is wrong, try again. But you
won&#39;t know something doesn&#39;t work if it&#39;s just an idea.</p>

<p>I became much more productive in everything. Not only MIT work stuff. Personal
(disposable) things I wanted to try.
<a href="http://shop.oreilly.com/product/0636920021810.do">Things</a> I wanted to learn.
<a href="http://shop.oreilly.com/product/0636920019664.do">Things I</a>
<a href="http://designinghypermediaapis.com/">wanted</a> <a href="http://objectsonrails.com/">to</a>
<a href="http://pragprog.com/book/warv/the-rails-view">read</a> (even my
<a href="http://instapaper.com">Instapaper</a> queue went down. By a lot!).</p>

<p>So, just try it out. It may take more than a week to get used to it, but just
try it. <strong>Close this post and every other distracting thing and do something</strong>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
